You guys have been telling me
that you're getting a lot of value from
critiquing
people's sales process. So today,
three more businesses, all wildly
different. If you want yours critiqued,
there's a link in the description.
Starting off with Jack Cottrell.
Very interesting.
The sobriety scene, I think,
could get very big.
Already established with 10,000 followers
on Instagram.
First thing I'd look at,
people always pin their highest-performing
posts.
But when we look down here,
we're probably averaging between one
and three, maybe
one and 4,000 views per reel.
I don't think this is enough because I
think there's a growing amount of people
that have a very poor relationship with
alcohol,
and I think most of them even know it.
Those of us that have done drugs,
we know that if we
were to do a double-blind
control study, cocaine, MDMA,
magic mushrooms, LSD, and
alcohol.
If you'd never been told about any of
those, you'd wake up and go,
"Alcohol is the worst one. Make
that one illegal." So massive seen here.
Now I am blind,
and you will have a better acoustic
experience if I put these on.
Every time you drink,
that could be a small amount
or a big amount, your brain
releases dopamine.
I think we need to maybe consider what you
say first thing in
every reel. That one wasn't, to me,
a good enough hook.
And again, this one,
"What's the best thing about being a sober
musician?" I don't
think enough people care because that's
about you, not this.
I hate. If I don't know you, keep in mind,
if I don't follow you, I
don't like you. It's just simple facts.
So everything we do in the beginning of a
reel, although we want to cater to our
audience, we also must appreciate
that maybe the majority of people don't
follow
us. Never do that again, please.
Thank you.
And again,
you've tried to get the caption to do the
work instead of the reel.
Not a fan.
Again, don't like that.
You're on a mope edge.
You're like,
"I'm going to film myself opening my mouth
as a hook." "What's the
hardest thing about being a sober
musician?" Again, I don't care,
and I'm saying
this in the kindest way that I can.
My life would be better sober.
I barely drink, but I still go back to it.
And when I do drink, I think,
"Jesus Christ, this
is hell on Earth." Why are these
hooks about you and not about people
that want to go sober?
Because if you really care about helping
people go on the same journey as you, you
should be making the content about them.
Yeah. So Instagram, I'm going to be harsh.
I'm surprised you got 10,000 followers
because these just aren't well thought
out.
Let me just make some up on the top of my
mind.
If you've been thinking about giving up
alcohol, here are some strategies you can
use to make it happen.
Have you ever done a dry January before?
And what did you learn doing it?
Ask yourself,
what's the longest you've gone
without alcohol? What is
that period of time?
And ask yourself,
did your life get better or worse
when you gave up alcohol?
Here's another one.
Don't you think it's crazy that
when you try and improve your
life by giving up alcohol,
people seem to think you've lost your
mind. Why is this?
Then maybe even some studies
that we could get into.
So I could ask ChatGPT,
can you cite any studies
that giving up alcohol is good for
your health? So for instance,
here already,
we're starting to get studies about
different things. What if I
was to tell you there's one thing you
could give up
that'll improve your mental health,
reduce your risk of cancer,
and reduce your
chance of getting cardiovascular disease?
And that thing is to stop drinking
alcohol.
I've been sober for three years,
and in this video,
I'm going to give you some
tips. You know what I mean.
Everything has to be about them,
the hooks, everything.
Now, annoyingly,
I come through to your landing page.
This video is a spectacular form of video
sales letter.
Because although it is your story,
you're giving a visual representation
and you're
showing us your journey.
And every journey is a story,
every story is a journey.
[rock music] Why you've decided to use
rock music and not a
voiceover, I will never understand.
[rock music] You've done so well with this
visual.
But instead, can you be your voice?
Three years ago, I was struggling in life,
didn't know what was next, and I was
drinking myself to death.
And then there was one thing I decided to
do that made my
life better forever.
And it wasn't actually something I did.
It was something that I stopped doing.
With this alcohol-free clarity reset,
you can, et cetera.
See, there's so much amazing stuff here.
Just think this needs to be tidied up a
bit. Now, this sounds interesting.
The seven-day alcohol-free clarity reset,
$37.
Now, when people say special offer,
regular price $260,
we know [chuckles] that's
not true. We just know it's not true.
It's like when people go, "Oh,
here's a free recipe book.
Original price $199." You're like,
"No one's ever paid $199 for a recipe
book."
Now,
if you're going to reduce something by 90%
off, you might as well just make
this free.
You might as well have a free resource
that people can use to get them
into your ecosystem.
Some of these visuals are fantastic,
and I'm very happy for
your personal journey.
And I'm sure there
are so many of these that you can
market. It's great.
But here's where I see your big
opportunity.
84 subscribers on YouTube. I think this
is the place that you want to
go.
So the biggest concern I see here with
your packaging, how I found ultimate
wealth, my sober transformation,
fat 25-year-old alcoholic.
Again,
we need to make these about the other
people. Alcohol destroyed my hopes.
So this could easily be turned around.
Is alcohol destroying your dreams?
What to learn from my six years sober.
I think some of the best things you can
look for.
So I don't actually like the packaging on
these two.
How to get sober on your own in 30 days.
This title is far too long.
Don't need to have hashtags in it.
How I got sober after 15 years.
But this advert here
is actually quite interesting.
I like the title, Stop Drinking From Home.
I think that's the title.
Let me cook. Oh, this is a good pic.
It's going to be perfect.
So we're going to take that picture,
pop it in here.
And again, real simple thumbnail. This
is your next video.
Maybe just some words on here
that just say stop.
Again,
I love a clean thumbnail at the moment.
Now, that is a bit jarring.
So what we're going to do
is probably just add a bit of an outer
glow,
or that's way too much, mate.
First of all, let's make this dark.
And maybe we just increase the spread of
that a tiny bit, maybe even a bit
smaller. Let's give this a go.
Then we go to trustedthumbsup.tv.
Let's have a look.
Stop drinking from home.
Something like that.
Just a beautiful...
And the reason we're saying this
is these guys would have
tested this thumbnail
if they're doing a paid ad.
Even another one,
how to commit to a path of sobriety.
Let's have a look what that looks like.
So that's idea one. That's another one.
That's the packaging.
Then you could just rift.
But when you start talking in your video,
just make sure you address them.
So you've got your own struggles,
but instead of going, "I was fat, I
was deflated,
I was depressed.
I didn't know where to go next.
I thought my life was going to end. I
was definitely addicted." You would start
and
say, "Are you overweight?
Are you feeling depressed?
Have you got low mood?
Are you aware that your relationship with
alcohol is ruining your life and you're
anxious that maybe
if you don't get on top of this,
that your life could be ruined
forever? Well,
I've been sober for six years
and there are eight pillars that are
imperative for you to understand
if you're going to start your own journey
of
sobriety. And in this video,
we're going to cover them off."
And then you get a lot
of time in front of people It's a good one
as well. How to stay sober for good.
They're all here.
How to stay sober for good. Wow.
This is just some unbelievable packaging.
You could have this for free, mate.
Have it for free, Jack. Yeah, 100%,
really work on the things that you're
going to talk about. And again,
if you're someone that's looking to go
sober, if
you want to stop snorting cocaine,
give up alcohol.
When was the last time you snorted cocaine
without drinking? Exactly.
Every single one of us never orders a bag
of cocaine till we're three beers deep.
So is the problem the cocaine
or the three beers?
Well, in my experience,
the second I gave up alcohol, et cetera.
Jack, I wish you well. Okay,
next one I came across was Forge Barbell.
Now, is this a person or is this a team?
Because I'm not going to connect with
Forge Barbell.
Forge Barbell can be the business,
but who is Forge
Barbell?
So when I see the jujitsu strength
company, I get excited.
One, because I do jujitsu,
and I think their SNC generally is just
undervalued. Now,
I'm not sure about this black
and white theme.
Looks a bit Schlinder's List-y for my
liking.
Now,
someone who is crushing it at the moment,
Charles Alum
Price. Amazing. Look at this.
Help BJJ athletes
and enthusiasts perform their best
on and off the mats. Amazing. Podcast.
Train with me.
Now, if we look at some of his reels,
some of these are getting amazing views.
Look at that. Average of maybe 30,000
or 40,000 views.
500 views on that.
This is a video of someone trying to
demonstrate that by performing exercises
that-
Okay,
I just want us to appreciate how great the
first three
seconds of this is
This is a video of someone trying to
demonstrate that by performing exercises
that
look like jujitsu is going to improve your
capacity to do those techniques at the
sport itself. This is not how-
So, the hook was about seven seconds.
He's initially said, we
are looking at people creating exercises
that are like
jujitsu. So we want to...
Should I be doing this? Is this right?
Am I wasting my time? Let's look
... it works. Jujitsu
is a sport that's heavily reliant on skill
acquisition and
general strength capacities. If you
are someone who's looking to get stronger
for
jujitsu,
the best way you're going to do that
is by building a strong foundation
through fundamental movement patterns,
like squatting, hinging, pushing,
pull-
Fantastic
This is a clip of Olympic caliber Russian
wrestlers.
The reason why I love this clip
is because a lot of people seem to think
that all
they did was wrestle
and not do any strength training, which
is absolutely not the
case. These-
So Charles is here every day,
breaking down common misconceptions.
And every video that I watch,
I'm thinking, "Wow, I'm learning
and bolstering to my
knowledge of jujitsu." And that over time.
There's only going to be a certain amount
of these that I can take before I say,
"Take my money, you son of a bitch.
I'm in." Whereas when I'm on your
Instagram, cool.
I'm just watching you bench in black
and white.
No, black and white don't work, bro. Cool.
You got some love from Thrudark. Cool.
200kg. This is impressive, brother.
This is really impressive.
But let me just throw something at you.
I don't care. And safety squat bar.
Why is this beneficial for grappling?
Why is this beneficial for jujitsu?
Help me understand. Cool. I'm not sold.
Where I'm on Charles's page, I'm learning,
I'm developing everything.
I'm building nuance.
I then see people doing stuff with certain
stuff.
I'm like,
"That's stupid," because Charles taught
me.
Online strength and conditioning for
jujitsu athletes and hobbyists.
Now, I don't mind this page.
Although about, plans, apparel, contact,
we're not
there yet. I like this. Strength
and conditioning for grapplers.
Our mission.
Someone needs to be front
and center of this brand.
Whoever it is, you need a Charles
or a person in there where you're like,
"We built
this community to make sure
that every time you grapple with someone,
they
go home,
and when they're sleeping with their
missus, they're just thinking about
your grip strength
or wondering how you got so hench
or so strong, or how you
worked that sumi gaeshi from butterfly
guard." I'm not seeing enough on
the front end to make me feel like I need
to give you my money. I'm just not.
And I think I can, and I will. Who
is Forge Barbell? I don't know.
There's no identity. With Charles,
I know who it is.
He's tapped me loads of times in training.
He's training in one of the most
competitive rooms in the world.
He's putting out content on a daily basis.
This guy also is doing something not
enough of us are really thinking about.
There is a new way of getting people to
become clients.
And the simplest way to do it is,
out of 100 people in your audience,
help 98%
for free. That's it.
And Charles here could go to a competition
and 98 people
fist bump him and go, "Mate,
your content is changing my life.
Never bought your program,
but your content is changing my life.
Cheers, bruv.
Spud." Because Charles knows that
if he can help 98 people out of 100
without them paying him, two people
are going to come along,
and they're just going
to get their wallet out and just say,
"Coach me,
bro." And the thing about Charles
is, let's have a look.
I want to actually look at this.
Train me one-to-one.
Join the Matt Strong program. Perfect.
You were doing so well.
A type form. Charles, brother, why?
Why are you hitting me with a type form?
Okay, all right.
Matt Strong Strength Conditioning,
29 bucks a month. Awesome. I like this.
I would love a landing page, Charles,
but I shall forgive you for now.
Okay, so we'll move on from Forge. Now,
this one, interesting.
Open Space Concepts. Home improvement.
I'm stepping out my lane. Now,
I did go to your website.
Now, I'm looking at this stuff.
And this is beautiful, mate.
Awnings, glass rooms, louvre pod,
glass verandas.
As someone who owns a home, basically,
what they don't tell you,
when you move into
a home, first of all,
you become obsessed with the local market.
You're always looking at houses.
I'm chatting to my missus' mom.
I'm like, "Dana, you seen
that house down the road?
Went for three mil.
Who's paying three mil for that?" Then
you're like, "Oh,
you'll never guess what's
come up on Fig Tree Street. No,
not the big house with the
veranda.
It's up." You turn into a little gossiping
neighbor.
"Oh,
you seen that fence they put up around the
corner?
Don't think they applied to the council
for permission for that one." Anyway, this
stuff excites me. Now, by the looks of it,
every person is
aspiring for you to come round
and do this kind of stuff to them.
Get a free quote, love it.
A few case studies, love it. Website,
I love it.
But on the Instagram,
there's one thing
that I feel we're missing.
And let's go through some of this.
[upbeat music]
Looks lovely.
Friday, everybody. Danny,
Open Space Concepts.
Now I've left this week's- Happy Monday,
everybody. Good morning, everybody.
Can anyone guess what we're missing? One,
two, three, ho.
So this looks amazing. This looks amazing,
mate. What a wonderful house.
What a lovely glass room.
But do you know what we haven't got?
What it looked like before.
Going to teach you a very simple thing
that I teach in
my mentorship.
Link's in the description
if you want to work with me.
If you see me in a bar
and I'm wearing a gold Rolex
and you don't know who I am,
you're going to think I'm a fucking piece
of shit bellend.
You're going to go, "Look at this twat.
Gold Rolex.
Look at him." But if someone was to say,
"Oh, that guy over there used to be a
personal trainer working in a budget gym
in Bracknell.
Over the last seven years,
he managed to make something of himself."
Now, whatever,
philanthropist,
whatever you want to call it.
You go, "Actually, maybe
that guy's all right." It wasn't me
that changed.
It wasn't the Rolex that changed. It
was the story with it.
So stories are very, very important.
If you show off really nice houses,
people are going to go, "Oh, rich people,
wankers." But if you show what it
was before and then the effort and the
workmanship that went into it,
you're going to draw people in.
Now, let's look into this.
If you want to know the best stories
ever.
I just bought
My arms shrunk. Of my all-time dream-
So we're showing the before crash damage
GT3 RS. And remember,
the reason I didn't get the GT3 RS was
because there wasn't enough storage,
not that I couldn't afford it.
But then as we go through,
we're watching the car bit by bit be
transformed.
This is what people want to see.
That's actually what all of this is,
is transformations.
Now, if we go to his Mark 2 channel,
we can look at some of his full builds.
GT3 here.
I just bought this wrecked Nissan GT-R,
which we th-
GT3, GT-R, cool. And through time,
we get to see the transformation.
And what people are waiting for
is to see the finished results. This
is it.
The past seven days- The dramatic music,
everything ... have led up to this moment.
Anything under 11 seconds is a w-
So we need to see something
transformative. What else
is there that's transformative? Oh my God.
The other thing people can't get enough of
is the Outdoor Boys.
Because,
let's have a look at his most popular
video.
Where's the one I watched the other day?
This one, right?
Dugout shelter under 10 foot,
3 meters of snow, 72 million views,
1.3 thousand views per hour. And this
is the most beautiful part, right?
He starts with nothing. He starts digging,
and what does he get by the end of it?
Lowest point in the shelter. The snow-
Humans ...
there is about five feet w-
Are so drawn to watching people build
stuff.
And what they want, and the reason
that people wait the whole way through
this, is
so they can watch
and see the finished product.
So if this guy was to start the video,
if he just starts the video in here, it's
not that interesting.
It's just a guy sat in a fucking igloo.
But the fact that he takes us on a story,
the fact that he starts with
nothing and he builds it,
that's the reason that you retain people.
Then at the end, he goes home.
Everything amazing on YouTube is some
kind of story. Even here, this guy,
professional cleaning a car, right?
Again, the car's filthy.
If he just shows a clean car,
no one cares.
But the reason that 93,000 people have
watched is because this is a story.
They're watching all the products get put
on.
They're getting to learn about the snow
foam and how it's making the car cleaner.
Story, story, story. Everything
is a story. Everything on Netflix
is a story.
Adolescence on Netflix is a story.
So going back to your point.
So at the moment,
we're not showing stories,
we're just showing endings.
And the thing that people really want to
aspire to is a before and after, and
that's the thing that I think
is missing from this.
And I think if you start showing people
before and after, we can do something
called a preview hook. So
if in the first few seconds we get a flash
of before,
after,
then we can go back to the beginning.
So for instance,
let's have a look at a back garden with
absolutely no warning,
looking a bit dirty, whatever,
before the build starts.
Then suddenly, scene change,
an amazing outdoor
monument.
And then just as you're about to pay off
what's been built, it could be
like,
[imitates drum] three months earlier.
And then you could just do a little time
lapse of all the stuff being built because
then you're showing something
that people want themselves.
Because they maybe don't want the end
result.
They want to see what it takes to get
there.
Because by showing just amazing gardens,
people can't relate.
But if you can show messy,
poor back gardens with poor architecture
and show really
poor befores, people can relate to that,
and then they can want to go on the
journey with you.
And I think that's going to just going to
get you way more eyes
on.
Then all of your projects turn into little
marketing projects as well, which
you can always repost
and put in other places.
And I think you can go super viral by
showing people, because you've
done the hard part, right?
Your products look amazing.
The stuff you do looks amazing.
You've done the hard part.
The easy part is just showcasing before
and after.
And there's no way
that people around the world aren't going
to want to see this.
What did I watch? Time lapse renovation.
These go off, mate. They go off.
Look at this, mate. People
are addicted to watching this stuff.
Granted, slightly different niche,
but I just guarantee that people...
I think I watched this one the other day.
I was mesmerized.
Tayla's like,
"We're going for dinner." I'm like,
"I'm busy.
I'm watching people renovate stuff." Now,
I'm not saying you have to go quite as
far as this, but it's a story.
I saw another mega viral one the other
day.
Okay, so look at this one here.
I turned a school bus into a luxury home.
This is a story. Beginning of the story.
They show, I think,
a glimpse of how it looks after than what
it was before.
Now they're showing some of the process of
it happening as a preview hook to get
people to retain this 26-minute video.
Then we start off with nothing,
like their back gardens,
and we end up paying them
off. So my question is for you,
Open Space Concept, if we just
showed that converted bus,
would it have got 27 million views?
Absolutely not. Why?
Because it lacks the story.
If you could start showing story in your
concepts, I think you'd do a lot better.
And if you are the main character of this
business, maybe you should be here.
So then I think this should be Danny Open
Space Concepts.
Danny at Open Space Concepts.
I think this could even be your name,
and then your
business could be underneath.
However you want to do it.
But Danny,
I think you need to start showing more
stories, more transformations.
I think it's going to revolutionize the
amount of people that come to your
business from social media.
Here's a quick one as well.
You need to post on TikTok more.
People will love and froth
over this shit on TikTok. Cool.
That's about it.
If you want to work with me,
link's in the descriptions. If not,
all good.
If you want to apply for this yourself,
there's also that link in the description.
Bye-bye.